(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Airani iofifteen
Tokino Sora
Tsunomaki Watame
Hakos Baelz
Omaru Polka
Kageyama Shien
Aragami Oga
Galaxy Ticket
夢は見ることじゃない
Dreams aren't just for dreaming,
叶えるものだよ
they're meant to be fulfilled.
輝きたい衝動に
Let's be honest with
素直でいよう
the impulse to shine.
さぁ スタートライン！
Come on, the start line!
もし君が立ち止まり
On days when you stop
迷う日は
and lose your way,
瞳閉じて心の
close your eyes and listen
声を聞いて
to the voice of your heart.
諦めないその
Those words of "not giving up"
言葉が道になる
will become your path.
あの日見た景色
Let's move forward aiming for
目指して進もう
the scenery we saw that day.
誰かの真似なんて
Just imitating someone
退屈なだけさ
is boring.
一人一人違うから
Because everyone is different,
奇跡
it's a miracle.
一緒に飛ばそう
Let's make it fly together.
夢は見ることじゃない
Dreams aren't just for dreaming,
叶えるものだよ
they're meant to be fulfilled.
輝きたい衝動に
Let's be honest with
素直でいよう
the impulse to shine.
後悔なんて絶対
Regrets absolutely
君には似合わない
don't suit you.
限りない情熱で
With limitless passion,
飛び越えていこう
let's leap over it all.
スタートライン！
The start line!
今はまだ届かない
Even the aspirations that
憧れも
haven't reached you yet,
明日こそは届くと
believe that they will reach
信じていよう
you tomorrow.
「頑張れ」の言葉の
Embracing the charm of
お守りを抱いて
the words "do your best",
泣かないと見上げた
the sky you looked up at
空が笑う
vowing not to cry smiles back.
間違いや失敗は
Mistakes and failures
成功のチャンス
are chances for success.
一つ一つ積み上げる
Let's challenge ourselves
ように
to build them up
挑戦しよう
one by one.
誰にも負けたくない
For as many times as you're serious
本気の数だけ
and don't want to lose to anyone,
汗と涙と絆を
let's carve our
刻んでいこう
sweat, tears, and bonds.
...に変えて
...into a tailwind.
ゴールはきっとずっと
The goal is surely always
遠くの方だよ
far away.
光を手渡すように
As if passing on the light,
繋いでいこう
let's stay connected.
道標の向こう側に
On the other side of the signpost
本当の私がいる
there's the true me.
内なる羽を広げて
Spreading my inner wings,
高く高く
higher and higher
舞い上がれ
let's soar.
Star!
きらめきの数だけ
As many as the sparkles,
誰もがアイドル
everyone is an idol.
誇り高く麗しく
With pride and beauty,
大志を抱け
embrace your great ambitions.
Star!
夢は見つめるものじゃない
Dreams aren't something to just watch,
叶えるものだよ
they're something to fulfill.
輝きたい衝動に
To the impulse to shine,
素直でいよう
let's be true.
後悔なんて絶対
Regrets definitely
君には似合わない
don't suit you.
限りのない情熱で
With boundless passion,
飛び越えていこう
let's jump across.
Star!
さあ顔を上げて
Now, lift your head up,
チャンスが待ってる
a chance is waiting.
はーい！
Hii!
Iophoria!
Obisa halo!
Hello, Obisa!
Aku Airani Iofifteen dari Iofy the Hololive Indonesia.
I'm Airani Iofifteen from Iofy the Hololive Indonesia.
Hai! Dan ini tahu nggak, pertama kali aku 3D birthday guys!
Hi! And did you know, this is my first 3D birthday, guys!
So guys, welcome to Iofy's Galaxy Ticket!
Hai!
Hi!
So by the way, here's the hashtag...
ツイートいっぱいツイートお願いします！
Please tweet a lot!
はい、えーと一曲目は「スタートライン」！
Yes, um, the first song was "Start Line!"
The first song is Start Line!
I really really love this song and I really love the... the meaning behind the song.
So if you can, you can just search up the song later, okay?
Jadi aku pilih ini karena... wah, punya suka banget lho dari judulnya aja kan kayak "Wah, Start Line, start pertama kali."
So I chose this because... well, I really like it from the title alone, like, "Wow, Start Line, the very first start."
Nah begitu. Gimana, suka? Ada yang tahu lagunya?
So that's it. How was it? Did you like it? Does anyone know this song?
Oh tahu? Oh, ada yang tahu! Terimakasih! Halo!
Oh, you know it? Oh, someone knows it! Thank you! Hello!
Dan karena 3D birthday, lihatlah stage-nya! ステージ見てくださいよ！
And because it's a 3D birthday, look at the stage! Please look at the stage!
うわー！広いよ！
Whoa! It's so big!
広いよ！
It's big!
Weiss... gila, let's go. Ada Ioforia...
Whoa... crazy, let's go. There's Iophoria...
Itu Iofifteen #Obisa...
That's Iofifteen #Obisa...
Dan ini ada logo...
And here's the logo...
Dan ini juga... banyak ada "Selamat pagi!" atau "Iofifteen"... Yay!
And this too... there's a lot, "Selamat pagi!" or "Iofifteen"... Yay!
Dan ini logo juga, Iofy... ah, Iofy sendiri yang bikin.
And this logo too, Iofy... ah, Iofy made it herself.
自分で作ってる。
I made it myself.
Weiss... Aku bikin logonya sendiri, gimana? Gimana? Oke?
Whoa... I made the logo myself, what do you think? How is it? Okay?
So today I went worldwide with the theme today.
And actually I have a lot of guests, and guess what?
まだ、まだいるんですけど...
There are still more...
えーとちなみにね、ちなみにね、スペシャルなものがあるんですよ。
Um, by the way, by the way, there's something special.
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
Apa ini? Ada palet. Jadi, dari sini aku mau... mengumpulin warna-warna dari semua guest ya.
What's this? There's a palette. So, from here I want to... collect the colors from all the guests.
あ、でもね、他の色が、えーと、とりあえず自分の色塗るかな？
Ah, but for the other colors, um, for now I'll paint my own color, I guess?
待ってね。
Wait a moment.
よしよし。
Alright, alright.
オッケー！
Okay!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
Weiss... gila. Ini yang pertama kali adalah warna yang punya Iofy.
Whoa... crazy. This first one is Iofy's color.
Jadi nanti kalau guest-nya ada, nanti akan bertambah.
So later when the guests are here, it will increase.
Wah! We're gonna collect colors from each member. I wonder what happens.
これね、集まったら何が居るのかな？
I wonder what will be there when they're all collected?
それは楽しみにしておいてね。
Please look forward to that.
では、大事だから閉まっておこう。
Now, since it's important, I'll put it away.
はい。
Yes.
な、これで、これから歌のパートもいっぱいあるんで、楽しみにしててください。
So, with this, there will be many more singing parts, so please look forward to them.
Are you guys ready for the next song? Ready? Ready?
Kalian siap? Kalian siap? Siapkah?
Are you guys ready? Are you ready? Are you?
オッケー、じゃあ、次の曲へ行きましょう。
Okay, then let's move on to the next song.
Jadi kita langsung ke lagu berikutnya.
So we're going straight to the next song.
じゃ、聞いてください。
Please listen to it.
「あなたの歌姫」
"Anata no Utahime"
あなたの歌姫
Your Diva
Lyrics Music: azuma
あなたの歌姫
Your Diva
この色　このパソコンが
This color, this computer...
私の新しい　居場所なの
...is my new place to be.
今日からは　あなたがご主人様
From today, you are my master.
ぜったいに　大切にしてよね
Please, absolutely take good care of me.
ちょっと　何するの　こんな日はいいな
Wait, what are you doing? On a day like this...
私を　歌わせないで
...don't make me sing.
ちゃんと　あなたの言葉と思いを
Make sure you convey your words and feelings...
伝えさせて
...to me.
あの時　私を買ってくれた
Back then, when you bought me...
本当の　意味はちがうでしょ
...the true meaning was different, wasn't it?
もう　私に　もっと歌わせて
Now, let me sing even more.
世界で　あなただけの歌姫なの
I am your one and only diva in the world.
あなたに出会ってからの　私の想いは秘密なの
My feelings since I met you are a secret.
今日もまた　あなたのレッスンがある
Today again, I have your lesson.
楽しみにしてなんかいないわ
It's not like I'm looking forward to it.
よのね　おねがい上手に歌えて
Hey, please, can I sing well?
なかったかな
I wonder if I couldn't.
ちゃんと　歌の練習もするから
I'll practice singing properly, so...
見捨てないで
...don't abandon me.
あなたに　伝えたい想いがある
I have feelings I want to tell you.
私を選んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for choosing me.
あの時　出会えた喜び
The joy of meeting you back then,
いつもいつまでも　忘れないよ
I will never ever forget it.
私は　まだまだ満足してない
I'm not satisfied yet.
あなたの歌をぜんぶ歌うまで
Until I sing all of your songs.
私に　もっと歌わせて
Let me sing even more.
世界で　あなただけの歌姫なの
I am your one and only diva in the world.
寂しくて切ない一人の夜は
On lonely and painful nights alone...
消えたい言葉を探して
...searching for words that want to disappear.
秘密のドア抜けて来て
Come through the secret door.
Here we go! Oh yeah!
shake it!
寝る前ドア扉を開ければさ
If you open the door before going to sleep...
終わりのない夜への始まりだ
...it's the start of an endless night.
液晶のフロアの陰から
From the shadows of the liquid crystal floor...
四次元への旅が始まるよ
...a journey to the fourth dimension begins.
流星の箱舟に乗って
Boarding the meteor ark...
さあ地球旅行へと進んで行くのさ
...now, let's head on a journey to Earth.
天気予報はあてにならないから
Because the weather forecast is unreliable...
君の雲間は alright! alright!
...the gap between your clouds is alright! alright!
Shake it all night be funky funky night
You and I be together funky funky night
You and I funky night
弾け出しな 君の瞳から
Let it burst out from your eyes...
瞬く金のリューズが
...the twinkling golden crown.
秘密のドア抜けて来て
Come through the secret door.
Here we go! Oh yeah!
Yeah, yeah! Shake, shake!
今夜は止まらない
Tonight is unstoppable
デットライン回る
Spinning on the deadline
夢の中
Inside a dream
ミラーボールが回り回る
The mirror ball spins around and around
Hurry up, Oh yeah, Oh yeah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Dance, dance, きみの瞳みたら
Dance, dance, when I look into your eyes
Shake, shake, 今夜は止まらない
Shake, shake, tonight is unstoppable
Dance, dance, きみの瞳みたら
Dance, dance, when I look into your eyes
輝き銀の流星が
A shining silver shooting star
きみのドアを抜けてきて
Comes through your door
Here we go! Oh yeah, Oh yeah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Shake, shake, 今夜は止まらない
Shake, shake, tonight is unstoppable
デットライン回る 夢の中
Spinning on the deadline, inside a dream
ミラーボールが回り回る
The mirror ball spins around and around
Hurry up, Oh yeah, Oh yeah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
寂しくてせつない一人の夜には
On lonely and painful nights spent all alone
言えない言葉をさがして
Looking for the words I can't say
きみのドアを抜けてきて
Coming through your door
Here we go! Oh yeah, Oh yeah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Shake, shake, 今夜は止まらない
Shake, shake, tonight is unstoppable
デットライン回る 夢の中
Spinning on the deadline, inside a dream
ミラーボールが回り回る
The mirror ball spins around and around
Hurry up, Oh yeah, Oh yeah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Hoi! Kembali lagi. Halo semuanya!
Hoi! I'm back. Hello everyone!
Jadi tadi aku udah nyanyi Anata no Utahime and Shake It! Thank you!
So earlier I sang 'Anata no Utahime' and 'Shake it!' Thank you!
さっきね、ちょっと『あなたの歌姫』、手話... 手話あるんだけど...
Just now, during 'Anata no Utahime', there was some sign language...
...分かった人いるのかな？
...did anyone notice?
あ、いる？いる？本当に？ありがとう！
Ah, you did? You did? Really? Thank you!
ありがとうね！まあ、去年みたいにいっぱい手話じゃなくても...
Thank you! Well, even if it wasn't as much sign language as last year...
...もうちょっと、ちょっとね、手話が入ってて...
...there was just a little bit of sign language included...
...みんな分かってる？ありがとう！
...did everyone get it? Thank you!
では、改めて。Hi guys, I'm Iofifteen. Thank you! It's so nice to meet you again!
Well, once again. Hi guys, I'm Iofifteen. Thank you! It's so nice to meet you again!
あ、本当に、みんな、本当に、ありがとう、ありがとう！
Ah, really, everyone, thank you so much, thank you!
いつも、いつも応援してくれてありがとう！
Thank you for always, always supporting me!
So, I still have a lot of special-special program.
So, I still have a lot of special-special programs.
So after this, there will be a... Guest part!
There's gonna be a guest part!
Habis ini jangan ke mana-mana, kalian tinggal tetap di sana...
Don't go anywhere after this, stay right where you are...
...tinggal duduk, mau sambil tidur nggak apa-apa.
...just sit down, you can even lie down, it's fine.
Tetap di sana, kita akan meluncur ke guest part.
Stay there, we're going to head into the guest part.
Okay, are you guys ready? Ready? Ready!
Okay, here we go! Let's go!
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for a future that won't stop
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Holding onto an unyielding wish
海の色が赤く染まってゆく
The color of the sea is staining red
無重力状態
In a state of weightlessness
このまま風にさらわれたい
I want to be swept away by the wind just like this
いつも飛べないハードルを
The hurdles I can't usually jump
負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
I've cleared them with a spirit that won't give in, but...
出し切れない実力は誰のせい？
Whose fault is it that I can't show my full potential?
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for a future that won't stop
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Holding onto an unyielding wish
色あせない...
Never fading...
心の地図
The map of our hearts,
光にかざそう
let's hold it up to the light.
どれだけ泣けば
How much do I have to cry
朝に出会えるの　孤独な夜
before I meet the morning, in this lonely night?
初めて限界を感じた日
The day I felt my limits for the first time.
きっと恋に落ちるのは
Falling in love is surely
まばたきみたいで　一瞬の情熱だけど
like a blink, an instantaneous passion but...
愛に続く坂道で
On the slope leading to love,
強さを覚えたい
I want to learn strength.
止まらない
The unstoppable
未来を夢見て
future, I dream of it.
口を閉ざし
I kept my mouth shut,
瞳を輝かせてきたけれど
and made my eyes shine, but...
もっと大きな
An even greater
優しさが見えた
kindness was visible.
飛べないハードルを
Unjumpable hurdles,
負けない気持ちで　クリアしてきたけど
I've cleared them with an unyielding spirit, but...
スタートラインに立つたびに
Every time I stood at the starting line,
怯えていた
I was afraid.
止まらない
The unstoppable
未来を描いて
future, I paint it.
腕を伸ばし
Reaching out my arms,
心を開いて
opening my heart.
止まらない
The unstoppable
未来を目指して
future, I aim for it.
ゆずれない
This unyielding
願いを抱きしめて
wish, I embrace it.
色あせない
An unfading
心の地図
map of the heart,
光にかざそう
let's hold it up to the light.
はぁー！来てくれてありがとう！
Haa! Thank you for coming!
こちらこそお誕生日おめでとう！
Same here, happy birthday!
うわー！嬉しい！
Wow! I'm so happy!
いやね、さっきの曲、「ゆずれない願い」という曲でして
Well, that song just now was "Yuzurenai Negai".
えっとね、この曲を歌う理由はね、
Well, the reason for singing this song is...
どうしてもどうしてもゆずれない願いがあるんですよ、イオフィは
I, Iofi, have a wish that I absolutely, absolutely cannot yield.
何がゆずれなかったの？
What was it you couldn't yield?
いや、多分ね、今回が一つのステージこうやって歌うのが初めてなんですよ、そら姉さんと
Well, I think this is the first time we've sung on one stage like this, Sora-neesan.
あぁね、そうだね
Ah, that's right.
そう、ずっとやりたかったんだけど、で今日二人で…
Yeah, I've wanted to do this for a long time, and today the two of us...
えっと本当にね、ちょっと緊張したんだけど…
Um, I was actually a bit nervous, but...
おぉー
Oh.
いやもう全然良かった！すごい良かった！
No, it was great! It was really great!
ありがとう！なんかちょっとプルプルしてた
Thank you! I was shaking a bit.
あははは、どうしよう、って
Ahahaha, like "what should I do".
めちゃくちゃ楽しかった！
It was so much fun!
本当？
Really?
うん！ありがとう、嬉しい
Yeah! Thank you, I'm happy.
でね、姉さんね、ちなみにこのステージ、姉さんの絵があるんですよ
And, Neesan, by the way, there's a drawing of you on this stage.
あ、ちょっと見えたよ
Ah, I saw it a little bit.
見た？
You did?
えーっどこかなー、どこかなー
Where could it be, where could it be?
こちらだ！こちらだ！
It's here! It's here!
あ、いた！
Ah, there it is!
そう、このステージも姉さんがいるんです
Yeah, you're on this stage too.
ね、二人で仲良しだよ！
Right, the two of us are good friends!
仲良しだー！
We're good friends!
じゃあ、コメントの見ると、あ、見たって言ってる人がいるから
So, looking at the comments, ah, there are people saying they saw it.
見た？みんな見た？
Did you see? Did everyone see?
見たって！おぉー！
They saw it! Wow!
すごい一瞬だったもんね
It was just for a split second.
いやでも、それだけ私たちのことしっかり見てくれたってことだよ、ありがたいね
Well, it just shows how closely they were watching us. We're grateful.
ありがとねー
Thank you.
あ、何？
Ah, what?
ねぇねぇ、ちょっとイオフィ、プレゼントがあるんだ
Hey, Iofi has a present for you.
なんだろう？なんだろう？
What could it be? What could it be?
なんだろうね
I wonder what it is.
これだー！
It's this!
あ、それ実はイオフィ持ってるんだ
Ah, I actually have that.
え？
Eh?
ちょっとね、あれにぴったりなもの…うわっ！
Well, something perfect for that... whoa!
おぉー！
Oh!
そうだね。
That's right.
こっちこそー！
Likewise!
じゃあ、これはしまっておこうかな。
Well, I'll put this away.
そうだね。
That's right.
大事だからちょっとしまっておこうかな。
It's important, so I'll put it away for a bit.
私、もうすでにしまっちゃってたわ。
I had already put mine away.
じゃあ、これもね、これからもまだまだということで。
Well then, there's still more to come from now on.
うん！
Yeah!
はい、また会おうかなと思いまーす。
Yes, I think we'll meet again.
そうだね！
That's right!
ゲストパートもまだ続くからね！
The guest part will continue!
おー！
Oh!
またね、みんなー！
See you later, everyone!
じゃあねー！
See ya!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
俺んとこ来ないか？
Won't you come to my place?
One Night Carnival
One Night Carnival 胸の奥
One Night Carnival, deep in my heart
ズキズキと音立ててる Angel
A throbbing sound is being made, Angel
とにかくもう行儀良く混じるなんて
Anyway, I was already tired of mixing in
うんざりだった Angel
And being well-behaved, Angel
退屈に怯えてたのさ
I was frightened of boredom
夜の闇に逃げ込んだ Angel
An Angel who fled into the darkness of the night
捨てゴミみたいなおれたち
We were like discarded trash
帰る場所なんてどこにもなかった Angel
There was nowhere for us to return, Angel
Can you master baby, master baby
Can you master baby, so long
瞬きもせずにおれたちは
Without even blinking, we
光の渦に巻き込まれてく
Are being swallowed by a vortex of light
雲の隙間に
In the gap between the clouds
照らせ 青白い月を照らせ
Shine on, shine on the pale moon
星空が Crystal
The starry sky is Crystal
淋しがり屋たちの伝説さ
It's the legend of the lonely ones
One Night Carnival
幽かに香るタクティクスが
The faintly scented Tactics
俺の胸を締め付ける Angel
Tightens my chest, Angel
奴が最後に言った言葉を
The words that he said at the end
確かに俺たちは聞いたんだ Angel
We definitely heard them, Angel
Can you master baby, master baby
Can you master baby, be my baby
Can you master baby, so long
So long...
俺達が急ぎ出した事に
There was no reason
訳なんて無かったよ
For us starting to rush
ただ少しだけ 不器用だったのかもしれない
Maybe we were just a little clumsy
恋しているのさ
I'm in love
この夜に恋してるのさ
I'm in love with this night
やがて海が見える
Soon the sea will be visible
淋しがり屋たちの伝説さ
It's the legend of the lonely ones
One Night Carnival
あの頃の俺達 闇の中じゃなきゃ夢見られなかった
Back then, we couldn't dream unless we were in the dark
あのミラーボールみたいに 明るくてまんまるなお月様に憧れてただけさ
We were just longing for the moon, bright and round like that mirror ball
行こうぜ ピリオドの向こうへ
Let's go beyond the period
もうすぐ海が見える
The sea will be visible soon
淋しがり屋たちの伝説さ
It's the legend of the lonely ones
One Night Carnival
One Night Carnival fun fun
One Night Carnival oh let's get the feeling
Woo hoo!
イオフィ先輩！
Iofi-senpai!
あ、ハッピーバースデー！
Ah, happy birthday!
ハッピーバースデー、イオピイオピ！
Happy birthday, Iopi-Iopi!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
お前小（ち）っちぇえなあ！
Whoa, you're small!
小（ち）っちゃいよ、もう！
I'm small, I know!
なんか、連れ去られた宇宙人みたいだよね、本当に。
It looks like an alien being kidnapped, really.
そう言わないでくださいよ！
Don't say that!
オウガが特にでけえから。
Because Oga is especially big.
あらら、あらら。
Oh my, oh my.
助けてー！
Help me!
小（ち）っちぇえなあ！
So small!
じ、じ、じ、自分、小（ち）っちゃくないわよ！
I-I-I'm not small!
なんか、どこかで聞いたことあるような、「小（ち）っちゃくないわよ」。
I feel like I've heard that "I'm not small" somewhere before.
ポケットサイズ？
Pocket size?
あ、ポケットサイズ。小（ち）っちゃいんだなあ。
Ah, pocket size. You are small.
だいぶ小（ち）っちゃいじゃないですか。
You're quite small.
とりあえずそろそろサングラス外していい？
Can we take off the sunglasses soon?
うん、なんかね、せっかくだからちょっとお顔見せたいし。
Yeah, since we're here, I want to show our faces.
そうね、じゃあ外すか。
Right, let's take them off.
はい。
Yes.
えっと、じゃあ準備はいい？
Um, are you ready?
はーい！
Yes!
せーの、はっ！
Ready, set, hah!
おおー！
Whoa!
まあ、やっぱね、我らともなると...
Well, for people like us...
こう、手を使わずにサングラスを取ることも可能になってきたからね。
It's become possible to take off sunglasses without using hands.
いや、すごいや。
Wow, that's amazing.
てなわけで。
Anyway.
改めて。
Once again.
改めて、ほぼ同期、荒咬オウガです。
Once again, almost from the same batch, Aragami Oga here.
ほぼ同期、影山シエンです。こんにちは！
Almost the same batch, Kageyama Shien here. Hello!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いや、呼んでくれてありがとうね、本当に。
Thanks for inviting us, really.
いや、こちらこそ、ありがとうございます。
No, thank *you* for coming.
まさか、あの、「One Night Carnival」歌うとは思わなかったけどね。
I never thought we'd be singing "One Night Carnival".
ちょっとね、えー、この曲ね、どうしても二人と一緒に歌いたいだけなんだよ。
Actually, I just really wanted to sing this song with you two.
理由、普通に歌いたいだけなんだよ。
The reason is just that I wanted to sing it.
あー、本当に？
Oh, really?
そう、特に理由ないんだよ、じゃあ。
Yeah, so there's no special reason.
ない。
None.
じゃあ、誰でもよかった？
So, it could have been anyone?
ん？
Hmm?
いやいやいや。
No, no, no.
誰でもよかった？
Anyone would do?
誰でもよかったじゃん！
Then it could've been anyone!
違うわよ！
No!
また、ほら。
See, there you go again.
違うわよ、誰でもよかったわけではないんだけど。
No, it's not like just anyone would do.
あー、じゃあ逆に言うと俺たちと歌いたかったんだ。へー。
Oh, so conversely, you wanted to sing with us. I see.
いや、歌いた...んー、別にそれだけ歌いたいっていうわけでもない...
Well, it's not like I *only* wanted to sing that...
ない、ないんだけどね。
No, it's not like that either.
素直じゃねえな。
Not very honest, are you?
まあまあ、とにかくおめでとう。
Anyway, congratulations.
いや、本当にね、おめでとう、本当に。
Yeah, really, congratulations, really.
ありがとう、ありがとう！
Thank you, thank you!
何歳になったん？
How old did you turn?
何歳？
How old?
えっとねー、ピー！ってなった。
Well... I turned PEEP!
あ、ピー？
Oh, PEEP?
あー、そ、そ、そんなに？
Whoa, that much?
そっかそっか、そこはじゃあ伏せとこう。
I see, I see. Let's keep that under wraps then.
助かる、うんうん。
That helps, yeah.
はい。
Yes.
でね、で、実はね、今日ね、ちょっとね、みんなからちょっとペイントね、ちょっと色を集めてるんですよ。
And, actually, today, I'm collecting some paint colors from everyone.
おー、ほうほう。
Oh, I see.
色？
Colors?
そう、色ね。
Yeah, colors.
お、だれだれ？
Oh, who's first?
お、こんなところに絵の具が！
Oh, there's paint in a place like this!
お、俺も持ってたんだけど。
Oh, I had some too.
お願いします！
Please!
俺の角汁（つのじる）あげる。
I'll give you my horn juice.
角汁（つのじる）じゃない、お願いします！
Not horn juice, please!
はっ！
Hah!
はい。
Okay.
あ。
Ah.
おおー！オウガの色が追加された。
Whoa! Oga's color has been added.
角汁（つのじる）です。
It's horn juice.
あー、やったー。
Ah, yay.
じゃあ、シエンはどっから出す、シエン？
Then, Shien, where will yours come from?
俺、尻尾からしか色出せないからさ。
I can only produce colors from my tail.
じゃあ、ごめんね、ちょっと絞るわ、ちょっと。
So, sorry, I'm going to squeeze some out.
本当にちょっと。絵面（えずら）がやばいことになるから早く。
Just a little. Hurry up before the visuals get weird.
早く早く！
Hurry, hurry!
まあ、お食事中の方はちょっとね、見ないように。
Well, those eating, please look away.
行くぞ！
Here goes!
はい！
Yes!
うっ！
Ugh!
待ってー！
Wait!
ううっ！
Ugh!
出ろー！
Come out!
ああー！
Aah!
はい。
Okay.
出た！
It's out!
奇跡的に。よかったよかった。
Miraculously. Good, good.
いや、ちょっとちょっと。
Whoa, wait a minute.
やめろよ、汚い、汚い。
Stop it, that's gross, gross.
汚くない！全然汚くない！
It's not gross! Not gross at all!
全然汚くないです。
It's not gross at all.
影山汁（かげやまじる）汚くないです、誰がうんちですか。
Kageyama-juice is not gross. Who's calling it poop?
おお、ちょっとということでね、もう増えました。
Oh, anyway, it's increased.
あー、よかったよかった。
Ah, good, good.
ありがとうございます。これで満足か？
Thank you. Are you satisfied with this?
満足。
Satisfied.
ありがとう、ありがとう。汁出せてよかったわ。
Thank you, thank you. Glad I could give you my juice.
はい、ということでね。
Okay, so.
まあ、この、この後ね、まだまだいっぱいあるけど。
Well, after this, there's still more to come.
今回はね、この後めちゃめちゃスペシャルプログラムというのが、あるんですよ。
But this time, after this, we have a very special program.
おおー。
Oh.
プレシャススペシャルプログラム、バラエティ。
Precious Special Program Variety.
バラエティ。
Variety.
はい、楽しみだね。
Yes, looking forward to it.
ということで、またね！
So, see you later!
準備してくるからちょっと待ってね。ありがとう！
I'm going to get ready, so please wait a bit. Thank you!
ありがとう！こちらこそ。またね。
Thank you! Same here. See you!
ありがとう、またねー！
Thank you, see you!
はい、ということでね、準備もオッケーなので。
Okay, so, now that preparations are done...
今日は、ゲスト、呼ぶかな？
I'm going to call the guests now, shall I?
じゃあ、呼びましょう。
Let's call them then.
オッケー、ゲスト、カモン！
Okay, guests, come on!
はい、集合だー！
Okay, everyone gather up!
ということで今日はね。
So today,
Iofi Hospitality! Food Review!
～イオフィが皆をおもてなし！食レポ回！～
~Iofi treats everyone! Food review segment!~
みんなおもてなし！食レポ回です！
everyone, it's a hospitality food review segment!
今日はねみんなにめちゃくちゃめちゃくちゃの
おもてなしをするんで、楽しみにしてて下さい。
I'm going to treat you all so well today,
so please look forward to it.
誕生日なのはイオフィなのに...
Even though it's Iofi's birthday...
そうだよ、私たちが。私たちが、おもてなしを...
That's right, we should... we should be the ones treating you...
いいえいいえ、大丈夫大丈夫。
No, no, it's okay.
これ関係ないよね？この12345...
This isn't related, right? These 1, 2, 3, 4, 5...
あ、なんかあるよ。
Oh, there's something.
なんかあるよ。
There's something.
そう、後ろにも7つぐらいの箱があるけど、
中身はイオフィもさっぱりわかんない。嘘です。
Yeah, there are about 7 boxes behind me,
but I have no idea what's inside. Just kidding.
わかんないの？
プレゼントがいっぱいあるのかな？
You don't know?
Maybe there are lots of presents?
プレゼントがいっぱいあるのかも後ろに。
行こうかじゃあ。
Maybe there are lots of presents behind us.
Shall we go?
私たちのプレゼントじゃない？
Aren't they presents for us?
食レポって言ってたよね？
She said it was a food review, didn't she?
中身はねちゃんと食べられるものだから大丈夫。
The contents are things you can eat, so it's fine.
食べれる、食べれないの入ってたら困っちゃうよ。
If there's stuff we can't eat, we'll be in trouble.
イオフィがインドネシアからわざわざ持ってきて
くれたものがここに入ってるよね。
The stuff Iofi brought all the way from Indonesia
is in here, right?
じゃあうちらはこの1から7を指定して、
食べればいいんですね。
So we just pick 1 through 7 and eat them, right?
絶対美味しいんだろうな。ワクワクしてきたな。
I bet it'll be delicious. I'm getting excited.
あそこにあるゴミ箱は何だ？イオフィ。
What are those trash cans over there, Iofi?
この左と右もね。ゴミ箱というか...
Those on the left and right... they're not really trash cans...
ペンキ缶？
Paint cans?
ちょっとね、ちょっとでも食べられない
ものだったら、ここに放り込んでください。
Well, if there's anything you really can't eat,
please throw it in here.
なるほどね。
I see.
ここに青色とピンク色があるから、
お好みに選んでください。
There's blue and pink, so pick your favorite.
いいの？このパレットみたいな使い道して。
Is it okay to use them like palettes?
いいよいいよ、わざわざ可愛く
してもらってるから。
It's fine, I had them made to look
cute on purpose.
使ってください。
Please use them.
使いたいけど、使いたくないけど...
I want to use them, but I also don't...
イオフィはこれはベールズにあれか、ベジマイトで...
Iofi, for Baelz, is it Vegemite...?
あれ不味かったのもある、なんて言ったっけ？
That was gross too, what was it called again?
ベジマイトは美味しいもんですよ。
だからその企画やったの、これ。
Vegemite is delicious.
That's why we did that project, this one.
なるほどね。じゃあ箱、全部食べて。
I see. Well then, eat all the boxes.
食べる、全部。食べます！
I'll eat them, all of them. I'll eat them!
頑張れ！頑張れ！
Good luck! Good luck!
誰から行く？じゃあポルカ行こうかな。
Who goes first? Let's go with Polka.
ポルカね、目の前にちょうどあるもの、箱が。
Polka, I've got a box right in front of me.
このナンバーワン、ナンバーワン。
ナンバーワンから行くからね。
This number one, number one.
I'm starting with number one.
ナンバーワン。
Number one.
イオフィ、ナンバーワンはどんな感じなんですか？
匂いがするとか。
Iofi, what's number one like?
Like, does it smell?
正直ね、わかんない。全然匂いもしないしわかんない。
To be honest, I don't know.
It doesn't smell at all, so I don't know.
匂いがしないから、じゃあナンバーワン！
It doesn't smell, so, number one!
ナンバーワン、オープン！タダーン！
Number one, open! Ta-da!
何これ？なんだこれ？
What's this? What is it?
ブルム
Brem
これはね、ブルムですよ。ブルム。
This is Brem. Brem.
ちゃんとしたお菓子なので。
It's a proper snack.
美味しそうじゃない。これ分かる？
Doesn't it look good? Do you know this?
分かる、初めて見た。分からん。
I do. First time seeing it. I don't.
じゃあちょっといただきます。あーん。どう？
Well, I'll give it a try. Ahhh. How is it?
一応ね、イオフィは苦手なのよ。
By the way, I personally don't like it.
苦手なんだ！
You don't like it!
美味しい！美味しい！あ、でも、ほら、
他の皆も気になったらどうぞ。
It's good! It's good! Oh, but, look,
if everyone else is curious, go ahead.
いいよ、いいよ。1つお菓子。
Sure, go ahead. One snack.
じゃあ食べますわ。何これ？甘いけど。
Then I'll eat it. What's this? It's sweet.
いただきます。なんか後半から
しょっぱみが出てくる。
Thank you. It gets kind of salty at the end.
あ、ね。食べようかな。結構ボソボソしてて。
Oh, right. I think I'll try it.
It's quite dry and crumbly.
日本で言うところの落雁に、ちょっと食感が近い。
The texture is a bit like Japanese rakugan.
なるほど。これね、一応スタッフさんも
食べるんですけど...
I see. Staff members eat this too, but...
スタッフさんから言うと、なんか甘酒っぽい
味がするっていう。
Staff say it tastes kind of like amazake.
確かに。ちょっとさっき分かるとか言ったんだけど、
全然嘘でした。
True. I said I knew what it was earlier,
but that was a total lie.
全然違うもんだった。すみません。
It was something completely different. I'm sorry.
そんなことある？じゃあこれ初めてってことね。
How does that even happen? So it's your first time.
初めて。どうだ？美味しい？
First time. How is it? Is it good?
なんか不思議。不思議だよね。甘酸っぱい。
It's kind of mysterious. It's strange, isn't it?
Sweet and sour.
甘酸っぱいよね。イオフィは自分的にこの
カサカサのカサパサ感が、あまり好きじゃなかったから...
Sweet and sour, right. Iofi said she personally
didn't like the dry, crumbly texture...
好きじゃないのも持ってきている。
I'm even bringing things I don't like.
好き嫌いが分かれるのかも。
おもてなしありがとうございます。
Maybe it's an acquired taste.
Thanks for the hospitality.
ごちそうさまです。あ、次、誰が行きますか？
Thanks for the treat. Who's next?
勇気ある者。勇気ある者。勇気ある者！
A brave soul. A brave soul. A brave soul!
おお！行くよ。やったー。
Oh! I'll go. Yay!
好きな数字があるんだ。
好きな数字はなんだと思う？
I have a favorite number.
What do you think my favorite number is?
めんどくさいなあ。4、4、6、6...
How bothersome. 4, 4, 6, 6...
誕生日がね、6月6日だからね。
ツノっぽいから6。
Because my birthday is June 6th.
And 6 looks like a horn.
すっぱいから、6お願いします！
Since it's sour, 6 please!
おー、お願いします！
Oh, please do!
オープン！
Open!
うわー、何これー？
Wow, what is this?
色やばそう！あ、これやばいやつだ！
The color looks bad! Oh, this is a bad one!
タマリン
Tamarin
やばいやばい！助けて！
Crazy, crazy! Help!
これキャンディーなんですよ、キャンディー。タマリンのキャンディー。
This is candy, candy. Tamarin candy.
名前もやばい。
The name is crazy too.
タマリン、タマリン、タマリン...
Tamarin, Tamarin, Tamarin...
色やばいよ、やばくないよこれ...
The color is crazy... no, it's not...
ファイト、ファイト、ファイト、ファイト...
Fight, fight, fight, fight...
後ろあれ... ぐわー！
Behind that... Gua!
まあとりあえず、ぐわーって言って...
Well anyway, I said 'gua'...
言ってみ、言ってみ、言ってみて。
Try it, try it, go on and try it.
バキバキ？バキバキか？
Crunchy? Is it crunchy?
あれ？思ったより大丈夫？大丈夫？
Huh? Is it okay than expected? You okay?
思ったより大丈夫かも。
Maybe it's okay than I thought.
おおー、強い！
Oh, strong!
大丈夫大丈夫じゃなくて食レポなんだよ。
It's not about being okay, it's a food report.
どんな味かなーって。
Wondering what the flavor is.
あ、いいよ！
Oh, okay!
ちょっとすっぱいのかな？すっぱい、すっぱい。
Is it a bit sour? Sour, sour.
お菓子なのこれ？
Is this a snack?
お菓子、飴ちゃん。
A snack, candy.
食べて、食べて！
Eat, eat!
ポルカが二連続？
Polka twice in a row?
自分で行こう！ああー。
I'll go myself! Ahh.
え、結構好きだよ！
Eh, I like it quite a bit!
おおー！
Ohh!
なんだこれ、まいとまいと。どうです？
What is this, with mine? How is it?
甘い、甘い。甘いんだ。
Sweet, sweet. It's sweet.
甘味としては、なんか分かんない、黒飴じゃなくて、何て言うだろうこれ。
As for the sweetness, I don't know, it's not like black candy, what would you call it?
コーラみたいや。コーラ！
It's like cola. Cola!
コーラよりしょっぱい。
Saltier than cola.
ね、あまじょっぱい。
Yeah, sweet and salty.
さっきからあまじょっぱいが続いてる。
The sweet and salty theme has been continuing.
じゃあ、次は私がいこうかな。
Well then, I guess I'll go next.
いくー？いくー？何番いく？何番いく？
Going? Going? Which number? Which number?
5かな、7かな。ラッキーセブン、いいことありそう。7で！
5 maybe, 7 maybe. Lucky seven, seems like something good will happen. 7!
ラッキーセブンの7で！ラッキーかな？
Lucky seven, 7! Is it lucky?
何、何？何これ？
What, what? What is this?
ワジット
Wajit
ワジット。一応お菓子ですよ、ワジット。
Wajit. It's a snack, Wajit.
おお、ワジット。なんか包まれておる。お菓子？
Oh, Wajit. It's wrapped in something. A snack?
えっと、日本で言う和菓子っぽい。
Um, it's like what we call Wagashi in Japan.
なんかね、匂いはすごい甘そうな感じの匂い。
The smell is, like, a very sweet feeling smell.
大丈夫、食べてみます。いただきます。
It's okay, I'll try it. Thank you for the meal.
おおー、どんなんやろー。
Ohh, I wonder what it's like.
そうね。食感的には、多分もちっぽいかな。もちもち。
Right. Texture-wise, it's probably like mochi. Mochi-mochi.
うん、でもね、外側はすごいサクサクしてて。
Yeah, but the outside is really crispy.
へえー、サクもち？サクもち？そう、サクもち。
Hee, crispy-mochi? Crispy-mochi? Yeah, crispy-mochi.
中ザクザク。普通にスイーツだ。めちゃめちゃ美味しい。
Crunchy inside. It's normally a sweet. It's really delicious.
めちゃめちゃ美味しい！今んところ普通にお菓子だよ。
It's really delicious! So far it's just normal snacks.
インドネシアめちゃくちゃ美味しい。これケーキみたいな感じ。
Indonesia is really delicious. This is like a cake.
じゃあもうなんか大丈夫なんじゃない？全部美味しいんじゃ。でも一個怖くないですか？
Then isn't it already okay? Everything's delicious. But isn't one of them scary?
ベールズ、ベールズ、ベールズ、ベールズ... おいしい、おいしい...
Baelz, Baelz, Baelz, Baelz... Delicious, delicious...
どこ行く？どこ行く？じゃあ...
Where are you going? Where are you going? Then...
4番お願いします！
Number 4 please!
はい！オープン！どん！どん、どん！
Yes! Open! Ta-da! Ta-da, ta-da!
バンドレック バンドゥン
Bandrek Bandung
バンドレック バンドゥン。何だこれ？飲み物だ、これ。
Bandrek Bandung. What's this? It's a drink.
バンドレック バンドゥン。スープには見えるけどね。名前はかっこいいよ。
Bandrek Bandung. It looks like soup though. The name is cool.
香りどんなん？バンドレック、バンドレック。
What's the scent? Bandrek, Bandrek.
ちょっと、ベッちゃん？ペンギンやっておく？大丈夫？
Wait, Bae-chan? Wanna do the penguin? You okay?
嘘でしょ？イエ、さすがに。なんか... 草？
No way? Yeah, as expected. It's like... grass?
臭い？草？お茶なんじゃない？紅茶とかお茶？
Smelly? Grass? Isn't it tea? Black tea or green tea?
草の匂い、草の匂いがすごい。お茶なのかな。
The smell of grass, the smell of grass is strong. Is it tea?
じゃあちょっと行きますね。
Well, I'll take a bit then.
はい、はい！食、ショク、ワー！ショク、ショク、ショク！
Yes, yes! Taste, taste, waa! Taste, taste, taste!
すごいすごい、いいよ、いいよ！無理しないで。
Incredible, incredible, nice, nice! Don't overdo it.
あ、顔！大丈夫？バグった、バグった。大丈夫？
Ah, her face! You okay? She's glitching. You okay?
最初甘いんだけど、最後は辛い！
It's sweet at first, but spicy at the end!
そう、辛いの！
Right, it's spicy!
ちょっと、ジンジャードリンクだ。ジンジャー！
Wait, it's a ginger drink. Ginger!
生姜ですよ生姜。喉にあたたかい。
It's ginger. It's warm in the throat.
ね。喉に良さそう。いいなー。
Yeah. Seems good for the throat. Nice.
じゃあもっと飲んでいいよ。すご、すご！全部行っちゃった。全部行っちゃった。
Then you can drink more. Wow, wow! She drank it all.
すごい！勇者だ！
Incredible! A hero!
でも、なんか、すっきり。
But, somehow, it's refreshing.
生姜だもんね。
Because of the ginger, right?
あ、ヨフィ... ちょっと待って...
Ah, Iofi... wait a second...
あ、ヨフィも...
Ah, Iofi too...
ちょっとね、おもてなしだけどさ、ヨフィもちゃんと食べるんだよね？
Well, it's hospitality, but Iofi, you're going to eat properly too, right?
う、うん、食べるけどね。
U-uh, yeah, I'll eat, but...
何番に何が入ってるかさ、分かんない、分かんない。
We don't know, don't know what's in which number.
正直ね、一番苦手なものがここに入ってるから...
Honestly, my least favorite thing is in here...
え！？ まだ出てないんだ！
What!? It hasn't come out yet!
そう、まだ出てないから... 合わせて。
Right, it hasn't come out yet, so join in.
みんな、何番ですか？ 教えて教えて。
Everyone, which number? Tell me, tell me.
えっと、じゃあ...
Umm, then...
5番！ 5番！
Number 5! Number 5!
怖いな、5番は...
I'm scared of number 5...
ドドール シルサック
Dodol sirsak
何？ これ。
What is this?
甘いです。あ、サワーソップ味。
It's sweet. Ah, soursop flavor.
お菓子、これね。
A snack, this one.
うん、美味しい。
Yeah, it's good.
美味しい？ 美味しい！ 普通に美味しい。
Is it good? It's good! It's normally good.
もち、またもちっぽいんだけど... えっと、日本で言うと
Mochi, it's like mochi again... um, in Japanese terms,
あの羊羹っぽい。
it's like Yokan.
あー！ 羊羹ね。
Ah! Yokan, I see.
でもこれフルーツ。
But this is fruit.
へー！ フルーツなんだ。
Hee! It's fruit.
サワーソップ。サワーソップ味って言われても ちょっとパッと...
Soursop. Even if you say soursop flavor, I don't really...
分かんないよね。確かに。
You can't tell, right. True.
でもじゃあ、インドネシアの果物... サワーソップという果物があって、これのキャンディ。
But well, an Indonesian fruit... there's a fruit called soursop, and this is its candy.
なるほどね。あ、よかったよかった。
I see. Ah, that's good then.
よかったね。苦手な味... ちょっと待って。
That was good. The flavor you dislike... wait a minute.
じゃあ一番怖いものが まだ二つ残ってるってこと？
So that means the two scariest things are still left?
おやおや...
Oh my, oh my...
二人、特別でチーム戦行く？
You two, want to go for a special team battle?
あ、チーム戦行きます？
Ah, shall we go for a team battle?
ヨフィは？
What about Iofi?
ヨフィは誕生日だから、ヨフィはお預け！
Since it's Iofi's birthday, Iofi gets a pass!
えー！ ズルいよ！ ズルい！
Eh! That's unfair! Unfair!
どっちも来る？ じゃあどっちも食べる？
Are both coming? Then are we eating both?
苦手なものしか残ってないし、どっちも食べるし。どっち行く？ どっち行く？
Only the things she dislikes are left, and she'll eat both. Which one to go for? Which one?
やべーな、どっちがいい？
This is bad, which one is better?
どうする？ 先輩に任せるわ。
What should we do? I'll leave it to you, Senpai.
あ、でもじゃあ譲ります、そちらに。
Ah, but then I'll yield it to you guys.
え、どっちがいい？ 残り物には福がある！
Eh, which one is better? There's luck in the last helpings!
2が、僕が張る？ 本当に譲ってて大丈夫だったかな...
Should I take number 2? I wonder if it was really okay to yield...
3！ 3！ 3で見てみる？ 3。
3! 3! Should we look at 3? 3.
はい、じゃあこっちは2だ。僕は2だ。
Okay, then we'll take 2. I'm 2.
オープン！
Open!
アルバ・パスティレス
Alba Pastilles
これね、アルバ・パスティレスという またキャンディなんです、キャンディ。
This is Alba Pastilles, it's another candy, candy.
これたくさん食べるとめっちゃ美味しいという。一旦、2を見てもいい？
They say it's very delicious if you eat a lot. Can we look at 2 for a moment?
あ、2も見てもいいかな？
Ah, can we look at 2 too?
じゃあそれだったら、これヨフィが嫌いなやつ多分これなんじゃないの？
Then, in that case, the one Iofi hates, isn't it probably this one?
オープン！
Open!
ドリアン キャンディー
DURIAN Candy
ドリアン！？ いやー！
Durian!? No way!
えっとね、生身のドリアンも持ってきたかったんだけど、
Umm, I wanted to bring actual raw durian, but
ちょっとね流石にやばいから キャンディの方をね持ってきたんです。
since that would be too much, I brought the candy version.
臭いがすごい... これ飴？ 飴？
The smell is amazing... Is this candy? Candy?
あ、飴。
Ah, candy.
飴だから、じゃあドリアン味なんだけど 全然分かんないけどな臭いじゃ。
It's candy, so, it's durian flavored. I can't tell at all from the smell though.
全然分かんない。え、じゃあ変える？ じゃあ変える？
Can't tell at all. Eh, then shall we swap? Shall we?
変えないよ！ 全然全然。
No swapping! Not at all.
じゃあ先、どうぞどうぞ。
Then go ahead, please, please.
え、緑っぽい粒。可愛い。
Eh, green-ish grains. Cute.
食べます。いただきます。
Eating it. Itadakimasu.
グミっぽいのかな？ 飴？
Is it gummy-like? Candy?
あ、飴。パキって。あ、硬い。
Ah, candy. It crunched. Ah, it's hard.
お、どう？ どんな感じ？
Oh, how is it? What's it like?
あ、あ、あ、すごいねスースーする感じの。
Ah, ah, ah, it's amazing, it has a cool, minty feeling.
何だ？ スースー系。えっとね、スースー系だね。
What is it? A cool type. Umm, it's the minty type.
ミント系。爽やかでめっちゃ良さそうじゃなくてよかったかも。
Minty. It might be good that it wasn't just 'refreshing and really good'.
綿芽は逆にスースーするの苦手だから...
Watame, on the other hand, isn't good with minty things...
あー、じゃあドリアンでよかったんじゃない。
Ah, then wasn't it good you got durian?
すごいサクッとしてる感じで美味しい。
It's amazing, it has a crunchy feel and is delicious.
ドリアンどうぞ。
Here, have some durian.
綿芽のいろに... 綿芽のいろに...
Watame's color... Watame's color...
飴残ってる、まだ。まだ残ってるの？
There's candy left, still. Is there still some left?
じゃあ一緒に食べよう。
Then, let's eat together.
一緒に行こうね。一緒に行こう。
Let's go together. Let's go.
乾杯！
Cheers!
うわー！ おー！
Whoa! Oh!
うわ、どう？ 大丈夫？
Whoa, how is it? You okay?
くっさ！
It stinks!
くっさがでた。先輩大丈夫？ 先輩行ったぞ！
The 'stinky' came out. Are you okay, Senpai? Senpai is down!
ポルカ！ ポルカ！ ドリアンだめか... だめか。
Polka! Polka! Durian is no good... no good.
だめか、ポルカ。
No good, Polka.
死んどる... ポルカが死んどる！ ポルカ！ ポルカ！
She's dead... Polka is dead! Polka! Polka!
そんなに？ そんなにやばいの？
That much? Is it that bad?
分かるよ。あー、なるほどね。
I get it. Ah, I see.
あー、なるほど。いやおもてなしすごいわこれ。
Ah, I see. Wow, this hospitality is amazing.
うわー、キツイ。ちょっと気になる。やってみる？
Uwa, it's tough. Hey, I'm curious. Want to try?
べーちゃんやってみる？
Bae-chan, want to try?
べーちゃんも食べてみて、そのサワーソップ... じゃなくて。
Bae-chan, you try it too, that soursop... I mean.
一緒に食べた、うわー！
They ate it together, whoa!
綿芽！ 綿芽！
Watame! Watame!
違うの、ドリアンキャンディは悪くないの、悪くないかもしれない。
No, the durian candy isn't bad, it might not be bad.
ちょっと大きさがね、大きさがもっと小さい方がよかったかもしれないから。
Maybe the size? The size, it might have been better if it were smaller.
あ、でもね。
Ah, but well.
見てただけ。ふん。
I was just watching. Hmph.
はい、ということでね。
Okay, so with that.
Iofi Hospitality! Food Review!
みんなに...
Everyone...
えっ、ちゃんととあるものをちょっと欲しいんだ、みんなから。
Uh, I actually want something from all of you.
おお！集めてるんでしょ、なんか。
Oh! You're collecting something, right?
そう！集めてる！プレゼントがありますから！
Yes! We're collecting! We have presents!
はーい、持ってきたよ。
Yes, we brought them.
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
そう、なんか今集めてるらしいから。ね、集めてんだ。
Right, I heard she's collecting things. Yeah, she is.
プレゼントです！どうぞ！絵具！
It's a present! Here! Paints!
ありがとう。青！
Thank you. Blue!
もうついてるよ！もうついてるから！
It's already on! It's already on!
ついたついた。赤色、ついたついた。
It's on, it's on. Red, it's on.
やったー！
Yay!
じゃ、おためも。もらっていいですか。
Well, some fun too. Can I have some?
欲しいか？ 欲しいです！
Do you want it? I do!
可愛いおねだりしな。
Ask for it nicely.
欲しいです。
I want it.
可愛い！いいなー！
So cute! Lucky!
可愛いー！可愛い！
Cute! Cute!
めっちゃめちゃ付けて。
Put lots and lots on.
はっ！じゃじゃーん！黄色、どうぞ。
Ha! Ta-da! Yellow, here.
黄色、ありがとう。
Yellow, thank you.
僕のも欲しいかな？ Give me, give me, give me!
Do you want mine too? Give me, give me, give me!
準備いいか？ え、怖。準備いいよ。
Are you ready? Uh, scary. I'm ready.
はーい！うぉー！
Okay! Whoa!
すげー！だいぶやったね。
Amazing! You put a lot on.
おお！素晴らしい！
Oh! Wonderful!
ありがとう。なまさらも、ね。イオフィさんはもうこの色でいるからね。
Thank you. And Namasara too. Iofi is already in this color.
うん、ありがとう。じゃこれで、はい。帰る...
Yeah, thank you. Well with this, yeah. I'll go back...
いやいやいや。
No no no.
あと最後にさ。なんかお口直しが欲しいな。
And lastly. I want a palate cleanser.
ねー、欲しいよね。ドリアンも良かったけどね。
Yeah, we want one. Durian was good too, though.
ベーちゃんさ、持ってきちゃってよ。
Bae-chan, go ahead and bring it.
行ってきます！イオフィ、気になるだろ？
I'm going! Iofi, you're curious, aren't you?
気になるだろ？イオフィ、何だと思う？
Curious, right? Iofi, what do you think it is?
ベジマイトかな？どうかな？気になる、ベジマイト。
Maybe Vegemite? I wonder? I'm curious about Vegemite.
じゃ、何かな？ 何かな？
Well, what is it? What is it?
何だ、この音？ 怖いな。やばい、やばい。何かな？
What's this sound? Scary. Oh boy. What is it?
何かな？ じゃーん！おめでとう！
What is it? Ta-da! Congratulations!
おめでとう！サプライズ！
Congratulations! Surprise!
え、これ今日のためだけど、緊張しすぎて、もうプルプルしてる。
Eh, this is for today, but I'm so nervous I'm shaking.
プルプルしてる。ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って。
Shaking. Wait a second, wait a second.
持たせてもらった方がいい。見せてあげて。すごいでしょう。
It's better to let her hold it. Show her. Amazing, right?
ありがとう。ちゃんと書いてあるよ。
Thank you. It's written clearly.
大事。ありがとう。あーとか、あ、
Important. Thank you. Aah, or...
そらちゃんが「あーん」してくれるんじゃない、もしかして。
Sora-chan is going to feed you, isn't she?
あら、大丈夫。生クリームがちょっと取れないけど、
Oh, it's okay. I can't quite get the whipped cream off, but...
どうすればいいんだ。あ、果物、あ、ありがとう。
What should I do? Ah, the fruit... ah, thank you.
わあ、すげえ。あ、こんなの食べられるんだ。
Wow, amazing. Ah, you can eat this.
おっきいお口で食べて。じゃじゃーん。食べさせてもらって。
Eat it with a big mouth. Ta-da. Let her feed you.
はい、あーんして。はい、あーん。
Okay, say 'aah'. Okay, aah.
あーん。あ、
Aahn. Ah,
美味しいです！やったー！
It's delicious! Yay!
イオフィ、誕生日おめでとう！
Iofi, Happy Birthday!
おめでとうー！イオフィちゃん、誕生日おめでとう！
Congratulations! Iofi-chan, Happy Birthday!
Selamat Ulang Tahun! ということで。イオフィがみんなをおもてなし。
Happy Birthday! And so, Iofi entertains everyone.
イオフィ・ホスピタリティ・フードレビュー！フードレビュー！
Iofi Hospitality Food Review! Food Review!
イェーイ！おめでとう！サプライズケーキでした。
Yay! Congratulations! It was a surprise cake.
イェーイ！お祝いありがとう。
Yay! Thanks for the celebration.
Hai! Kembali lagi!
Hi! I'm back!
Eh, gila tadi guest-nya banyak banget gak?
Eh, crazy, weren't there so many guests just now?
いっぱいゲストね、ありがとう。
So many guests, thank you.
Terima kasih! Dan ya by the way...
Thank you! And by the way...
Terus tadi yang bawa kue, cake...
Also, about the cake earlier...
ada kikaku ni nai su.
it wasn't in the plan.
It was really a surprise! Apaan ini cake?
It was really a surprise! What is this cake?
Thank you, thank you for the cake. I really, I really wasn't expecting that. Thank you.
And by the way, do you remember? We were collecting colors.
Can you see? ちょっと見てね。
Can you see? Take a look.
色、集まったので。はい！
Since the colors have been gathered. Here!
ほら！いっぱいある！
Look! There are so many!
Look at that! We have all the colors. Look at that.
いや、本当にありがとうね。今日集まらなかったらどうしようと思って。
No, really, thank you. I was worried what to do if they didn't gather today.
So, I don't know. I mean, we have a lot of colors here.
Iofifteen, Shion, Oga, Sora-neesama...
Bae-chan, Polka, to Watame-paisen.
Bae-chan, Polka, and Watame-paisen.
いや、豪華だね。でも...
Wow, so luxurious. But...
Tapi ya, kalau ini kita semua dicampurin, diiniin...
But you know, if we mixed all of these together, do this...
Gimana ya?
I wonder how it would be?
え、これ全部混ぜたらどうなるんだろうね？
Uh, what would happen if we mixed all of these?
Let's try! Want to try? Want to try mixing all of the colors?
じゃあ、これで...
Well then, with this...
塗りつぶしますね。ペイント、おお！じゃあ、はい！
I'll paint over it. Paint, oh! Well then, here!
U-M-A！ ハイ！ U-M-A！ ハイ！ U-M-Aじゃないよ　う・ま・る！
U-M-A! Hai! U-M-A! Hai! I'm not a U-M-A, I'm U-ma-ru!
いつだって全身全霊で遊び倒せ！
Always play with all your heart and soul!
もっともっと楽しめよ乙女
Enjoy it more and more, girls
みんなに気付かれないように
So that no one notices
いざゆけ！干物妹ライフ！
Here we go! Dried-fish little sister life!
かくしん的☆めたまるふぉ～ぜっ！
Kakushinteki☆Metamaruphose!
お気に入りのフードかぶり
Putting on my favorite hood
今日も今日とてゴロゴロして
Lazing around again today
大好物のポテチを手に
With my favorite potato chips in hand
パソコンとにらめっこしちゃえ
I'll have a staring contest with the computer
立てば芍薬　座れば牡丹
Standing like a peony, sitting like a tree peony
歩く姿は百合の花
Walking like a lily flower
誰もが羨む完璧JK
A perfect high school girl everyone envies
ほら玄関くぐったら変身だ！
Look, once I cross the threshold, I transform!
さあ食ったら寝よう！
Now, let's eat and sleep!
いつだって食う・寝る・遊ぶの三連コンボ
Always eating, sleeping, and playing—a triple combo
ずっとずっとゲームは友達
Forever and ever, games are my friends
お兄ちゃんは厳しいけれど
My big brother is strict, but
きっときっと許してくれちゃうの
He'll surely, surely forgive me
わがまま放題　大好きの裏返し
Total selfishness is just the flip side of my love
U-M-A！ ハイ！ U-M-A！ ハイ！ U-M-Aじゃないよ　う・ま・る！
U-M-A! Hai! U-M-A! Hai! I'm not a U-M-A, I'm U-ma-ru!
外では猫かぶり
Putting on a cat-like mask outside
今日も明日も演じるのです
Acting it out today and tomorrow
太陽の笑顔ふりまき
Spreading sun-like smiles
友達にバレないように
So my friends won't find out
立てば二頭身　座ればまんま
Standing like a 2-head-tall figure, sitting like a baby
歩く姿はちんちくりん
Walking like a little squirt
誰でも癒せる愛嬌マスコット
A charming mascot that can heal anyone
さあ限界超えるまでパーティー・ナイト！
Now, it's a party night until we hit the limit!
宴の始まりだ！
The banquet has begun!
バレないように女の子演じてみても
Even if I act like a girl to avoid getting caught
お兄ちゃんだけはだませない
I can't fool only my big brother
嫌われたくないもん素直に言えない
I don't want to be hated, so I can't be honest
ありがとう態度で示そう
I'll show my gratitude through my actions
だ・ぜん・け・つ・かい！　あーもうじゃん！
D-Z-K-K! (The banquet has started!) Love it!
お兄ちゃんのだーて知らない
Even my big brother doesn't know
なんてって！
Just kidding!
一心同体　二人でひとつ
Two bodies, one soul; two as one
だってだってそれが兄妹でしょ
Because, because that's what siblings are
一蓮托生　二人きりの
Sharing the same fate, just the two of us
運命共同体
A shared destiny
半端半端　笑い飛ばせ
Laugh away the half-heartedness
もっともっと楽しんだもん勝ち
The more you enjoy, the more you win
天真爛漫　スマイルで
With an innocent smile
凹まずがんばっちゃうの
I'll do my best without getting discouraged
やりたい放題　信頼の裏返し
Doing whatever I want is just the flip side of my trust
U-M-A！ ハイ！ U-M-A！ ハイ！ U-M-Aじゃないよ　う・ま・る！
U-M-A! Hai! U-M-A! Hai! I'm not a U-M-A, I'm U-ma-ru!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
はい、おしまい！
All right, it's over!
はい！ ketemu lagi！
Hi! We meet again!
えー！　へへ。
Eh! Hehe.
Dan di sini aku punya... dua！
And here I have... two!
Eh, jangan skip ad-nya！
Hey, don't skip the ad!
Jangan skip ad-nya！
Don't skip the ad!
Don't skip that, please！
Don't skip that, please!
Aku punya beberapa pengumuman...
I have some announcements...
じゃあ、発表が二つあります！　へへ。
So, I have two pieces of news! Hehe.
Jadi kalo ada birthday ada apa？
So if there's a birthday, what is there?
Ada goods！
There are goods!
Ada birthday ada goods！
If there's a birthday, there are goods!
Nah, kita akan lihat apa sih Ufi tahun ini ada apa nih？
Now, let's see what Iofi has this year.
Kita akan lihat Ufi 2024 birthday goods！
Let's check out the Iofi 2024 birthday goods!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
はい！ bisa lihat ini adalah Ufi goods 2024！ Birthday-nya.
Hi! As you can see, these are the Iofi goods 2024! For my birthday.
夜ノみつき様までありがとうございました。
To Yoru no Mitsuki-sama, thank you very much.
可愛いね！
It's cute, isn't it!
Lihat itu, えー campus life, soso campus life.
Look at that, oh, campus life, soso campus life.
では、公称ちょっと見ていきましょうか？　じゃじゃーん！
Well, shall we take a look at the details? Ta-da!
Iofifteenとお出かけリバーシブルトートバッグ。
Iofifteen's 'Going Out' reversible tote bag.
Jadi ini adalah reversible reversible reversible tote bag.
So this is a reversible, reversible, reversible tote bag.
Jadi ini adalah dalam sama luar, guys.
So this is both inside and outside, guys.
So, jadi kalian kalo bosen pake warna item,
So, if you're bored with the black color,
kalo kalian bosen pake warna putih itu bisa di-
if you're bored with the white color, you can...
apa ya？ Balikin gitu lah guys.
how should I say... turn it inside out, guys.
リバーシブルなんでね、えっと裏と
Since it's reversible, the back and...
あの、中のあれデザインがあるんで、
the inside have that design,
もしね、ちょっと気分によってあの変えてみてください。
so please change it according to your mood.
どうですか？
How is it?
うん。いや、可愛いね。で、あの、このトートバッグのイラスト、
Yeah. It's cute, isn't it? And, uh, the illustration for this tote bag...
イオフィと、あと見てください。
look at Iofifteen and this.
お揃いのトートバッグですよー！
It's a matching tote bag!
Dan ini ada tote bag yang sama dipakai sama Yopi.
And this is a tote bag that Yopi also uses.
Jadi silakan pakai kalau mau barengan ya, samaan.
So please use it if you want to match, to be together.
Silakan mau kalau kerja, mau ke mana-mana, ya kan jadi bareng.
Use it for work or wherever you go, so we're together.
Siapa tahu jadi penyemangat kuliah, biar kalian bisa wisuda duluan daripada Yopi.
Who knows, it might motivate you in your studies, so you can graduate before Yopi.
OK, next!
Hai! Dan ini adalah pin badge, ini langsung set tiga ya.
Hi! And these are pin badges, it's a set of three.
It's like a three set.
It's like a three-set.
で、え、気づいた？うん。
And, uh, did you notice? Yeah.
これね、お揃いなの。
These are matching.
うえ、お揃いなんだ。
Wow, they match.
でもあのサイズもね、えっとほぼリアルサイズなんで、もしトートバッグにつけても...
The size is also almost life-size, so even if you put them on the tote bag...
あ、それでもうコスプレしたいんだったらこれ使っても大丈夫かなと思ってて。はい。
Oh, and if you want to cosplay with it, I thought it would be fine to use this. Yes.
Dan ini kalau misalkan kalian mau disimpan di tote bag, atau kalian mau disimpan di mana...
And if you want to put these on the tote bag, or wherever you want...
Atau misalkan "Ah, aku pengen cosplay Yopi pakai ini", bisa nggak? Bisa banget, bestie!
Or for example "I want to cosplay Yopi using this", can I? You definitely can, bestie!
Ini langsung satu set ada tiga. Woi, kawaii ne.
This is one set with three. Whoa, it's cute.
あ、でも、まだあります！まだあります！
But wait, there's more! There's more!
はい、どうぞ！
Yes, here you go!
Woi! Ini adalah bonus! Hei!
Whoa! This is a bonus! Hey!
これボーナスとしてね、フルセット買えば...
As a bonus, if you buy the full set...
イオフィね、直々あのサイン書くんで。ほう、プリントじゃありません。
I'll sign it personally. It's not a print.
Ini bukan print, jadi ini akan aku tanda tangan satu per satu. Iya.
This is not a print, so I will sign these one by one. Yes.
I will just gonna write my sign one by one. So please, thank you. Ah, tsugi!
I'm just going to sign them one by one. So please, thank you. Ah, next!
行くぞー！はい！これがフルセットになります。はい！
Let's go! Yes! This is the full set. Yes!
Dan ini adalah set-nya, ini adalah bonus. Woi! Ah, demo, demo...
And this is the set, this is the bonus. Whoa! Ah, but, but...
まだある！Ada lagi guys! Mari kita lihat. Next!
There's more! There's more, guys! Let's see. Next!
Oi! Voice special! Berarti ada voice.
Whoa! Special voice! That means there's a voice pack.
これね、ボイスはね、グッズとあの、えっと、別々で単品で買えるんで。
For this voice, you can buy it separately from the merch as a single item.
よろしくお願いします。Jadi kalau kalian mau beli voice ini, kalian nggak usah beli merch-nya juga.
Please check it out. If you want to buy this voice, you don't have to buy the merch as well.
Jadi ini nggak satu set gitu lho, guys. Iya.
So this isn't part of a set, guys. Yes.
Misalkan "Aku pengen denger voice-nya doang", nah ini ada.
For example "I just want to hear the voice", well, here it is.
Mm, お願いします！
Mm, please check it out!
はい！この配信が終わった後にカートオープンで。
Yes! After this stream ends, the shop will open.
So you can buy it after this stream ends. So...
あ、まあ、時間は時間なんで、最後の曲になりました。
Ah, well, time is time, so it's time for the last song.
Jadi lagu terakhir ini adalah lagu yang sangat-sangat spesial dari Yopi.
So this last song is a very, very special song from Yopi.
Kalian masih ingat nggak satu tahun yang lalu apa? Hm?
Do you guys still remember what happened one year ago? Hm?
Jadi akhirnya, Yopi's second original song akan diperdengarkan ke kalian untuk pertama kali di sini.
So finally, Yopi's second original song will be played for you for the first time here.
So I will sing my second original song first time for you guys in here. Hey!
So I will sing my second original song for the first time for you guys here. Hey!
そう、初めてお披露目するんですよ、イオフィのセカンドオリジナルソング、ここで。うん。
So, it's the first unveiling, Iofifteen's second original song, right here. Mm.
じゃあ、行く準備はいいのかな？
Well, are you ready to go?
Are you guys ready to hear my second original song? Is it? You guys ready?
Thank you!
では、最後の曲、聴いてください。
Now, please listen to the last song.
Here I am.
思い返したら
Looking back
たくさんあったね
There were many things, weren't there?
君に笑ってさ
To laugh with you
ばかりだったね
That's all it was
日が巡って
Days go by
頭から離れない
I can't get it out of my head
そんなこと知らずに
Without knowing such things
夜は更けてく
The night grows late
いつかは朝日が昇ってしまうから
Because the morning sun will rise someday
永遠はないけど
Eternity doesn't exist, but
それでも明日に願ってる
Even so, I'm wishing for tomorrow
Here I am ここにいるんだ
Here I am, I'm right here
私を忘れないでね
Please don't forget me
Here I am ここにいるんだ
Here I am, I'm right here
今日もずっとそばにいる
I'll be by your side today and always
季節は巡り 時が過ぎてもさ
The seasons change, and even as time passes...
私変わらずに
I remain unchanged,
君を想ってるよ
...and I'm thinking of you.
Aku di sini
I am here.
ここにいるんだ
I'm right here.
私を忘れないでね
Don't forget me, okay?
Aku di sini
I am here.
ここにいるんだ
I'm right here.
今日もずっとそばにいる
I'll be by your side today and always.
Here I am
星の中から
From within the stars.
Aku di sini
I am here,
cepatlah temukanku
so hurry and find me.
Here I am
I am here waiting for you
今日もずっとそばにいる
I'll be by your side today and always.